Your Royal Highness, could you convince your people
殿下，你能否让你的人民相信
they were not being attacked by Earthmen?
他们并不是被地球人攻击的
(SIGHING) If only we had proof.
除非我们有证据
Then I could convince my people
and you could convince yours.
那样我就可以说服我的人民，你也能说服你的
But there's not much time.
但我们没有太多时间
Madam President, everything is ready.
We shall use my personal scoutship.
总统夫人，一切准备就绪了。我们用我个人的侦察舰
We'd better leave at once. Madam President.
我们最好马上离开，总统夫人
- My life at your command.
- Madam President.
- 听候您的差遣  - 总统夫人
DOCTOR: Right, 34 seconds,
找到了，34 秒
a course correction to galactic
coordinates 2349-6784.
航线调整为星际坐标 2349-6784
You realise where that will take us?
你知道那会带我们去哪儿吗？
A completely uninhabited sector
of the galaxy.
这个星系中一片完全无人居住的区域
Well, not completely uninhabited,
General Williams.
嗯，也不是完全无人居住，威廉将军
That's where the Ogron's planet is.
Orgons 的星球就在那里
No doubt your information is better than mine.
当然，你的信息比我全
- May I ask where you obtained it?
- Certainly. From the Master.
- 我能问问从哪儿知道的吗？ - 没问题。从法师那里
He fed the co-ordinates into his
ship's computer when I was his prisoner.
他之前把坐标输入到飞船电脑里面了，那会儿我还是他的俘虏
And after you'd captured the ship, sir,
在你捕获这艘飞船之后
I extracted the information
from the ship's memory banks.
我把这信息从飞船的记忆库中提取出来了
We're simply wasting time...
我们纯粹是在浪费时间...
Dragons!
龙族人！
Let me talk to them, I shall explain!
让我来跟他们说，我可以解释
Somehow I don't think they're in the mood
我怎么觉得他们这会儿没这个心情
for explanations at this minute.
根本不给我们解释的机会
- Can you outrun them?
- This ship can outrun anything.
- 你能跑得过他们吗？ - 这艘船跑得过任何船
Hyper-drive. Max hyper-drive!
超驱模式，开到最大！
- Right, we're out of range now.
- Reduce speed, return to course.
- 好了，现在够不着我们了  - 减速，回归原航线
MASTER: They should be here very soon now.
他们应该很快就到了
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Judging by the size of the ship, they can't be in any great force.
从飞船的大小来看, 他们的力量不可能太强
So conceal yourselves and ambush them
as soon as they arrive, right?
所以你们隐藏起来, 他们一到达就伏击他们，行吧？
Hold on, wait a minute.
Something's happened.
停，等一下。有点情况
They must have landed very nearby.
他们肯定已经在很近的地方着陆了
Right, send out patrols!
好，派出巡逻队
Get them and bring them
back here immediately.
抓住他们，立刻带回这里
And, remember, I want the Doctor alive.
并且记着，博士我要活的
OGRONS: Yes, Master.
是，法师
One dominant life form,
a large and savage reptile.
一种处于统治地位的生命形式，体型巨大，行为野蛮的爬行动物
Yes, well, let's hope
we don't encounter one.
好吧，期望我们一个也不要碰到
Doctor, has it occurred to you
what we're going to do
博士，你有没有想过我们该做什么...
when we discover the source of this signal?
...等我们找到这个信号的源头的时候？
I've no idea, old chap.
We'll find out when we get there.
我也没概念，老伙计，我们到了那儿应该就能发现了
Come on, can't be far.
快来，应该不远了
- Drop! Surrender!
- WILLIAMS: Take cover!
- 放下武器！投降！  - 隐蔽！
(GROWLING)
What is that?
那是什么？
I've no idea, but whatever it is,
it's on our side.
我也不知道，但不管是什么，它在帮我们
Yes, I await your arrival with the greatest of pleasure.
是的，我怀着极大的喜悦等待着你们的到来
And I shall be there to meet you
the moment that your ship touches down.
你们的飞船一沾地，我就在那里迎接你们
(OGRONS GRUNTING)
- So, where's the Doctor?
- The monster came.
- 怎么，博士在哪儿？  - 怪兽出来了
The monster?
And I suppose you all ran like rabbits?
怪兽？然后你们就跟兔子一样乱跑了？
- We fear the monster!
- You stupid, cowardly idiots!
- 我们害怕怪兽！ - 你们这群愚蠢、胆怯的笨蛋！
You will answer to your masters for this.
你们自己答复你们的主人吧
- What? They are coming?
- Yes, they are coming!
- 什么，他们到了？  - 是的，到了
Which means that I can dispense
with your doubtful assistance.
也就是我可以不要你们帮倒忙了
Out of my way!
给我闪开！
Hello, Doctor!
你好，博士！
So here you are at last, eh?
看来你终于到了，哈？
- Surrender or you'll be shot down!
- No, he's unarmed.
- 投降，要不然把你打下来！ - 不，他没武器
Unarmed maybe, but not unaccompanied.
可能是没武器，但并不算没帮手
I've brought some old friends along
to meet you.
我带来了一些老朋友跟你见见面
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Quite a touching little reunion.
多么令人感动的小重逢啊
(MASTER LAUGHING)
CHIEF DALEK: Doctor, you are in our
power and you will be exterminated.
博士，你在我们掌控之中了，你会被终结
- No, not yet.
-You will obey the Daleks!
- 不，还不要  - 你要服从 Daleks!
You know as well as I do
that this man does not fear death.
你们跟我一样清楚，这个人并不怕死
I want him to suffer a much worse punishment.
我希望他受到更严重的惩罚
Look, my skill and cunning
has brought about this war
听着，我靠我的技巧和狡猾挑起了这场战争
which will make you the masters of the galaxy.
而这场战争可以让你们成为这个星系的主人
Leave the Doctor with me
and let him see the result of that war.
把博士留给我，让他看看这场战争的结局
Let him see the galaxy in ruins.
让他看着这个星系变成废墟
Let him see the planet Earth,
that he loves so much, in ruins,
让他看着他深爱的地球变成废墟
then exterminate him.
然后再终结他
Very well. He will remain your prisoner
until the war is concluded.
好。他仍然是你的俘虏，直到战争结束
Then you will bring him to us
and we shall exterminate him.
然后你带他过来，我们会终结他
We shall now return to our base
and prepare the army of the Daleks.
我们现在返回我们的基地，准备 Daleks 军队
Oh, I suppose I should thank you
for saving my life?
噢，我觉得我应该感谢你救了我一命？
Not for long, Doctor.
It's going to be a very short war.
不会太久的，博士，这将是一场很短暂的战争
Right, take them away.
好了，把他们带走
- Hello, Doctor.
- Hello, Jo.
- 你好，博士  - 你好，Jo
Oh, so now they've got all of us.
噢，这样一来他们把我们所有人都抓了
All except the pilot. He's repairing the ship.
驾驶员还没，他在维修飞船
Why do these Dalek creatures wish
to set your people and mine at war?
为什么这些叫 Dalek 的东西期望你们和我们之间发生战争？
'Cause war will mean the extermination
of both empires, Your Royal Highness,
因为战争就意味着两个帝国的终结，殿下
and the Daleks will emerge
as the supreme rulers.
然后 Daleks 就会成为最高统治者
Now somehow, we've got to get
out of here and stop them.
现在，我们得想个什么方法逃出这里，然后阻止他们
(WHISPERING) Doctor! Doctor,
would the Master's little fear-box help?
博士！博士，法师的这个恐惧小盒子有用吗？
Well done, Jo!
干得好，Jo！
You see, we could use it
to frighten the Ogrons away
你们看，我们可以用它把那些 Ogrons 吓跑
and then we can all escape.
然后我就都可以逃走了
Well, that's hardly practical, Miss Grant.
这，不太好操作，Grant 小姐
They'd just run off and we'd still be locked in.
即使他们跑掉，我们还是关在里面
(SIGHING) Oh!
噢！
There is one thing we can do, though,
and it'll need a very slight adjustment.
不过，还有一个方法我们可以用，只需要做一点很小的调整
There's nothing to worry about.
没有什么可担心的
The Doctor will be perfectly safe
in my hands.
博士在我手中会很安全
And I promise you,
when I deliver him to you,
而我向你保证，当我把他交给你们的时候
he'll be a broken man.
他将是个废人
CHIEF DALEK OVER RADIO:
Do not fail the Daleks.
不要让 Daleks 失望
The war is certain now.
现在这仗是肯定要打了
And once the great empires
have destroyed each other,
一旦这两大帝国摧毁了对方
I ask but one thing, let me rule
the planet Earth in your name.
我只要求一件事情：让我以你们的名义统治地球
General Williams,
if we do manage to get out of here,
威廉将军，如果我们设法逃了出去
and Jo and I manage to create a diversion,
而Jo 和 我设法把他们引开了
could you find your way back
to your spaceship?
你能找到回到自己飞船的路吗？
- Certainly.
- Good.
- 当然  - 很好
Right, that should do it.
好，这样应该可以了
Now I want you to take off immediately.
我要你们立刻起飞
Get the truth back
to your respective governments.
把真相带回给各自的政府
Yes.
好
Tell them that they must mount
a joint expedition
告诉他们必须建立一支联合的远征军
- and capture this base at once.
- I shall stay and help.
- 要立刻攻占这个基地
- 我留下来帮忙
No, we'll need you to convince
the Emperor, Your Royal Highness.
不，我们需要你去说服皇帝，殿下
What about you and Miss Grant,
how will you get away?
你和 Grant 小姐怎么办，你们怎么逃走？
Jo, I presume that the TARDIS
is still here?
Jo，我估计 TARDIS 仍然在这里？
- Yes, I know where it is.
- Well, don't worry about us.
- 是的，我知道它在哪儿  - 那，不用担心我们了
- Our spaceship is here.
- That's all very well, Doctor,
- 我们的飞船在这里  - 那就太好了，博士
but we still happen to be locked in.
不过目前我们还是被锁在这里面啊
Yes, well, would you mind blocking your ears
是。不过你们不介意捂一下耳朵吧
and covering your eyes just for a moment?
眼睛也要盖住一会儿
I do not understand.
我没搞懂
No, but I think you will in a moment.
Just do as I ask, would you?
过一会儿你就能懂了。按我说的做，好吗？
- You, too, Jo.
- Oh, no, it's all right.
- 你也是，Jo  - 噢，不用，没事的
- I can resist it.
- Can you?
- 我能抵抗住  - 能吗？
- Yes.
- Good.
- 是的  - 好
DOCTOR: Uh, how much longer are you
gonna keep us locked in here?
啊，你们还能把我们锁在这里多久？
Yes, I'm talking to you.
是的，跟你说话呢
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
Open the gate. Open the gate.
把门打开，把门打开
Open the gate or I will exterminate you.
把门打开，否则我终结你
It worked.
生效了
DOCTOR: Right.
JO: Come on, then. Follow me.
- 好
- 快点，跟着我
CHIEF DALEK OVER RADIO:
Do not fail the Daleks.
不要让 Daleks 失望
(SCOFFING)
Right, we'll see who rules
the galaxy when this is over.
行，等这事完了，我们来看看谁是这个星系的统治者
(MOCKINGLY IMPERSONATING THE DALEKS)
"Do not fail the Daleks", indeed!
“不要让 Daleks 失望“，真事似的
You stupid, tin boxes!
你们这些愚蠢的铁桶
(OGRON GASPING)
Why aren't you guarding the prisoners?
你为什么不看守着俘虏？
- The Daleks sent me away.
- There are no Daleks!
- Dalek 把我派开了  - 现在没有 Daleks！
- The Daleks have all left the planet.
- The Dalek said to open the cell.
- 他们已经离开这个星球了  - 那个 Dalek 说让我打开牢房
Did he now? Fetch the others!
I want them here immediately.
他说了？把其他人找来，我要他们马上到这里来
- Doctor, look at this.
- DOCTOR: Well, that's fascinating.
- 博士，看看这个  - 嗯，很迷人
Is it some sort of idol?
I saw one of the Ogrons worshipping it.
会不会是某种偶像？我看见一个 Ogrons 在拜它
Yes, I'm not surprised.
We've seen the real thing, haven't we?
哦，我不会奇怪的。我们刚才见过这种生物，是吧
They're probably more frightened of him
than they are of the Daleks.
他们可能更害怕他, 更甚过害怕 Daleks
Right, come on. This way.
好了，快来，这边
Right, you can get out this way. Good luck.
来，你可以从这条路出去。好运
- And you, Miss Grant. Doctor.
- General Williams.
- 你也是，Grant 小姐，博士
- 威廉将军
WILLIAMS: Farewell.
JO: Good luck.
- 再见  - 祝你好运
DOCTOR: Your Royal Highness.
PRINCE: My life at your command.
- 殿下  - 听候您的差遣
The TARDIS is over there.
TARDIS 就在那边
Going somewhere, Doctor?
要去哪儿，博士？
You know, you really are incredibly
persistent, aren't you?
知道吗，你还真是阴魂不散啊，是吧？
- That is my property, I believe.
- Oh, yes, a most ingenious device.
- 那是我的东西，我想  - 是的，这个设备做得很精巧
I congratulate you.
我恭喜你
OGRONS: Oh! The monster!
哦，有怪兽！
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
- Oh, Doctor, I thought you were dead.
- Help me.
- 噢，博士，我还以为你已经死了  - 帮我一下
Come on, yes. Careful.
加油，好，小心点
- Help me into the TARDIS, Jo.
- Okay.
- 扶我进 TARDIS 去，Jo  - 好
- All right, Jo.
- Careful.
- 好了，Jo  - 小心点
The first thing we've got to do
is get out of here.
我们要做的第一件事，就是离开这里
(WHOOSHING)
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士，你在做什么？
Telepathic circuits,
sending a message to the Time Lords.
心灵感应回路，给时间领主传递一个信息